Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ bhanukaharischandra (LinkedIn) linktr.ee/bhanoob (Portfolio) www.forbes.com/profile/bhanukaharischandra/ (Other)

Top Skills

Marketing Strategy Entrepreneurship Business Strategy

Languages

Sinhalese (Native or Bilingual) English (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

RoW100 - Global Tech Changemakers Forbes 30 under 30

Bhanuka Harischandra

Forbes 30 under 30 - Digital Strategy, Product + Growth Sri Lanka

Summary

Bhanuka Harischandra is a "self-taught" marketer that believes in testing and adapting and not conforming to set rules. His unstructured yet intentional approach to problem-solving acts as the fundamental lens in which he helps businesses grow through the use of digital marketing, technology and data.

His career in the media and technology space began at 19, with the launch of "TheGamersCottage" a YouTube Multi-Channel Network that helped over 600 content creators monetize over half a billion eSports video views. Through this, he quickly came to understand how to 'speak' to different audiences in the digital landscape and the power behind content distribution.

After being approached by a number of local businesses, Bhanuka established Surge Global, a digital media and technology company to focus on the needs of helping businesses grow in the online space. In 2018, he captured the eye and imagination of Senior Executives within the Tavistock Group, who invested in the company and helped pivot the business to focus on the some of the groups most strategic and valuable investments.

Today Surge works with fortune 500 companies globally to empower brands with sophisticated storytelling, content distribution and actionable insight. Over the last 5 years, Bhanuka has successfully led the digital strategy for a multibillion-dollar US smart city, a UK based lending organization, Australia's oldest operating company, A technology company servicing the publishing industry.

He is a celebrated Entrepreneur, TEDx Speaker and is a part of the prestigious Forbes 30 under 30. In his spare time, Bhanuka helps incubate and accelerate early stage startups under his investment organization SeedingAlpha currently employing over 200 people across different ventures.

Experience

Surge Global 8 years 11 months

Founder & Chief Executive Officer April 2023 - Present (6 months) Colombo, Western Province, Sri Lanka

Founder & Chief Growth Officer April 2019 - April 2023 (4 years 1 month) Colombo, Sri Lanka

Currently helping businesses understand their digital strategy and scaling marketing + tech teams to drive revenue, growth and explore new opportunities through tech.

Founder & Chief Executive Officer November 2014 - April 2019 (4 years 6 months) Colombo, Sri Lanka

Surge provides digital strategy & implementation to businesses that require growth marketing and product development. With experience from global brands from seed funding to publicly listed enterprises.

Working with an extensive client list in both the B2B and Consumer space across Technology, Agriculture, Healthcare, Automotive, Transportation, Finance, E-commerce, Food & Bev etc.

Simplebooks.com
Co-Founder & Chief Executive Officer
November 2016 - October 2017 (1 year)
Sri Lanka

When you start a passion project & you turn it into a company, you quickly realized that you've signed on for a lot more paperwork than you had in mind.

We realize that you want to work on what you love, but you can't let go of your accounting and finances as well. We'll take it off your plate, send you your accounts every single month, fully sorted out.

The Gamers Cottage
Founder & Chief Executive Officer
January 2014 - December 2015 (2 years)

The Gamers Cottage is a gaming community website as well as a YouTube Network. Comprised of reviews and tutorials of various games in various genres, providing unique content for their users.

Our goal is to make Gaming a greater experience by showing members which games are play worthy and those that aren't, we provide tutorials on a large and expanding Archives channel as well as produce videos for your viewing pleasure.

We help gaming content creators build a revenue doing what they love.

Education

Ananda College, Colombo Sri Lanka Biology, Physics, Chemistry